# THOMAS ARCHBOLD

32 Purbrook Estate, Tower Bridge Road, London, SE1 3BZ tomjarchbold@gmail.com  $\diamond +44~7837~674~419 \diamond$  tomarchbold.com

#### BACKGROUND

I am a Ph.D. student at King's College London where I am part of the Distributed Artificial Intelligence group. My research interests are in algorithmic game theory and mechanism design, as well as other areas of theoretical computer science such as algorithms and complexity theory.

#### **EDUCATION**

## MPhil/Ph.D. Computer Science, King's College London

2020-2024 (expected)

Research interests: algorithmic game theory, mechanism design, theoretical computer science

Supervisor: Professor Carmine Ventre

# MSc. Computer Science, University of Warwick

2019-2020

Classification: Distinction

Dissertation title: A Decentralised Peer-Prediction Market (awarded distinction)

## BSc. (Hons) Computer Science, University of Warwick

2016-2019

Classification: 2-1

Dissertation title: An Educational Kernel for the Raspberry Pi (awarded first class)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Graduate Teaching Assistant, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

- 6CCS3OME Optimization Methods

2020/21

Private Tutor Oct 2020-present

Tutor for GCSE Computer Science. Involves planning and delivering one-on-one lessons, delivering feedback, and collectively deciding on which topics to focus.

### Software Graphics Engineer Intern, Imagination Technologies, Kings Langley

Jul 2019-Sep 2019

Worked with the PowerVR Vulkan driver team researching Google's ANGLE API to analyse its performance on the driver, and wrote OpenGLES and Vulkan programs to test specific areas of its functionality.

Contributed driver code and was involved in weekly team meetings to discuss progress and plans for the coming week.

#### POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

# Seminar Organiser, Distributed Artificial Intelligence group, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

Help to organise the fortnightly seminar within the Distributed Artificial Intelligence research group, which involves contacting internal and external speakers to present talks on their work and chairing the meetings.

#### Conference Student Volunteer

- International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP)

Jul 2021

# Conference sub-reviewer

- Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT)

Jun 2021

# Presenter, International Conference for Undergraduate Research 2018

Sep 2018

Presented an individual research project on "Cellular Automata and Computational Universality" at the ICUR.

Produced an introductory primer on cellular automata and their applications as well as software to visualise them.

## LANGUAGES AND SKILLS

Programming Languages

C, C++, Python, Lisp, Java, Bash

Tools Languages Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Keras, GDB, Valgrind, Git, LATEX

French (B2/upper intermediate)

Russian (B1/intermediate)

## WIDER ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

First XV Player of the Season, University of Warwick RFC

2019/20, 2018/19

UWRFC First XV, QE Boys Rugby First XV, QE Boys Cricket First XI

2016-20, 2014-16, 2015-16

# REFERENCES

Available upon request